<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Resources on Enchantment in the History of Capitalism</title>
    <link>https://economic-enchantments.net/resources/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Resources on Enchantment in the History of Capitalism</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 08:23:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://economic-enchantments.net/resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A conversation with Will Pooley</title>
      <link>https://economic-enchantments.net/resources/podcast-pooley/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://economic-enchantments.net/resources/podcast-pooley/</guid>
      <description>Will Pooley is a Senior Lecturer in Modern History at the University of Bristol.
Transcript 00:00:00 Kristof Welcome, everyone, to an episode of the summer podcast of the Research Network Enchantment in the History of Capitalism. We&amp;rsquo;re a very interdisciplinary group of scholars that get together to explore the different ways enchantment can be a methodological tool, conceptual structure, or a driving force one way or other in histories of capitalism and in the past month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A conversation with Michael Saler</title>
      <link>https://economic-enchantments.net/resources/podcast-saler/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://economic-enchantments.net/resources/podcast-saler/</guid>
      <description>Michael Saler is Professor of History at the University of California, Davis.
Transcript 00:00:01 Kristof Welcome, dear listeners, to the podcast of Enchantment in the History of Capitalism. We are a young research network that aims to conceptualize enchantment, I suppose to better understand the history of capitalism, either as a tool, or as a structure, or as a founding principle of economic markets or institutions or relationships. And with &amp;lsquo;we&amp;rsquo; I mostly mean Anat Rosenberg Astrid Van den Bossche, the two initiators of the network who in the spring started with a series of roundtables in which we got scholars together to talk about enchantment and how we can think about enchantment in terms of capitalism.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
