<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Enchantment in the History of Capitalism</title>
    <link>https://economic-enchantments.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Enchantment in the History of Capitalism</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 08:21:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://economic-enchantments.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A conversation with Michael Saler</title>
      <link>https://economic-enchantments.net/resources/podcast-saler/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://economic-enchantments.net/resources/podcast-saler/</guid>
      <description>Michael Saler is Professor of History at the University of California, Davis.
Transcript 00:00:01 Kristof Welcome, dear listeners, to the podcast of Enchantment in the History of Capitalism. We are a young research network that aims to conceptualize enchantment, I suppose to better understand the history of capitalism, either as a tool, or as a structure, or as a founding principle of economic markets or institutions or relationships. And with &amp;lsquo;we&amp;rsquo; I mostly mean Anat Rosenberg Astrid Van den Bossche, the two initiators of the network who in the spring started with a series of roundtables in which we got scholars together to talk about enchantment and how we can think about enchantment in terms of capitalism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enchantment in contemporary scholarship on economic life</title>
      <link>https://economic-enchantments.net/events/roundtable-2022-05-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://economic-enchantments.net/events/roundtable-2022-05-05/</guid>
      <description>A roundtable with Professor Jean Comaroff, Professor Jens Beckert, and Professor Robert Kozinets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enchantment in the history of science, literature, and art</title>
      <link>https://economic-enchantments.net/events/roundtable-2022-03-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://economic-enchantments.net/events/roundtable-2022-03-25/</guid>
      <description>A roundtable with Professor David Morgan and Professor Carrie Tirado Bramen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://economic-enchantments.net/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 08:32:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://economic-enchantments.net/contact/</guid>
      <description>Join our mailing list here: ECONOMIC-ENCHANTMENTS@JISCMAIL.AC.UK
Do you have questions, suggestions, or would you like to send in a proposal for a work-in-progress presentation?
You will find us on Twitter:
Astrid: @askebos Anat: @anat_rosenberg Kristof: @kristof_smeyers Or send us a message:
&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roundtables</title>
      <link>https://economic-enchantments.net/events/index-roundtables_archived/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 08:23:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://economic-enchantments.net/events/index-roundtables_archived/</guid>
      <description>At the moment, our activities are focused on running a series of roundtables to converge discussion around a set of leading texts that represent existing conceptual and historical scholarship on enchantment in modernity, from the fields of theology, anthropology, the history of science, literature and art, philosophy, marketing and business.
The goal is to map existing knowledge as well as draw out theoretical points of contention through joint readings and discussion of a set of questions relevant for the history of capitalism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://economic-enchantments.net/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 08:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://economic-enchantments.net/about/</guid>
      <description>We’re a network of scholars who seek to develop enchantment as an organizing theme in historical studies of capitalism. We hope to provide a platform for those interested in the historical role of enchantment as a tool, structure, or foundation for the organisation and the development of modern markets, economic institutions, and economic relationships.
Activities From February to May 2022, we ran a series of roundtables to converge discussion around a set of leading texts that represent existing conceptual and historical scholarship on enchantment in modernity, from the fields of theology, anthropology, the history of science, literature and art, philosophy, marketing and business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People</title>
      <link>https://economic-enchantments.net/people/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 08:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://economic-enchantments.net/people/</guid>
      <description>Network coordinators Anat Rosenberg is a senior lecturer at the Harry Radzyner Law School, Reichman University, Israel. Her work concerns the cultural legal history of capitalism, liberalism and consumption in Britain, and methodologies of law and the humanities. She is author of Liberalizing Contracts: Nineteenth Century Promises Through Literature, Law and History (2018), and The Rise of Mass Advertising: Law, Enchantment and the Cultural Boundaries of British Modernity (forthcoming).
Kristof Smeyers is a Postdoctoral Fellow at the Ruusbroec Institute, University of Antwerp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enchantment in theology and scholarship on magic</title>
      <link>https://economic-enchantments.net/events/roundtable-2022-02-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://economic-enchantments.net/events/roundtable-2022-02-24/</guid>
      <description>A roundtable with Professor Owen Davies and Professor Jason Ānanda Josephson Storm</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
